Okay. Um maybe you're like me and you've
noticed now that um there's a difference
between the way we were handling strings
in the last video and the way we were
handling numbers in the last few videos.
Um, so if you think back to how we
manipulated a string, if we had a string
and we called it my name and set it
equal to Bruce Wayne and we wanted to
pull a subsection out of that, we said
my name dot and then we did sub string
or substr, whichever one you preferred.
And you'll notice the syntax for that
was variable name dot and then something
you wanted to do with it. However, when
we wanted to manipulate um numbers like
take the square root of something um we
had a number like let my or we'll just
take this random number that we
generated here and if we wanted to um
take the square root of that then we had
to say maths
square root my num.
So in this case we were accessing an
outside library and using the square
root function um rather than just using
our variable name dot and then the
function we wanted to use.
So that was because we were covering the
math library there. Actually just like
there are with strings where you can say
my name dot and you can see everything
you could do with the string. There is a
similar thing for numbers. So, I'm going
to say my number equals 10.
And then I could say my number dot and
then you can see a list of things you
can do with it. So, uh the first one
we're going to talk about is two fixed.
So, two fixed is how you round numbers.
So, if I have 10.998
and I round want to round it to two
decimal places, then I'm going to use my
num.2fixed too fixed.
So the way this works is we'll say alert
my num oh not my name my num dot to
fixed and then we put the parenthesis.
Now I'm going to pause here to explain
the hint that pops up when you pop up
the hint. It says fraction digits and it
wants you to give a number and this is
the number of digits after the decimal
point and it must be in the range of 0
to 20 inclusive. So, you could have it
round to zero digits or you could have
it round to 20 digits after the decimal
place. In this case, I want to round it
to just oh, actually, let me make those
numbers something that will round a
little better. Um, so I want to round it
to the second decimal place after the
digit. So, if I put a two and I save
that, if we come over to our web
browser, we can see it rounded to 10.99.
So the reason I changed that was because
if this was a nine and we round it to
two decimal places and we reload the
page, it rounds to 11 because it rounds
up the nine and that becomes a 10. So
you carry the one and it rounds all the
way up to 11. So um two fixed allows you
to specify the number of decimal the
number of digits after the decimal
place.
Um, some other things you can do with my
numbers. You can say my num dot Oh, I
deleted my number. Sorry. We'll say let
my num equal
10.
You can say my num dot and you can say
to string. When you do this, it takes
your number and converts it into a
string. So it takes this 10 without
quotes and turns it into a 10 with
quotes.
So if we alert and we go back to a
concept we covered in a previous video
where we did type of. So if we said
alert the type of my num.2 string then
the message we get is that this should
be a string. So if we come over here and
we reload our page we get that this is a
string. So if you want to convert
something from a number into a string,
you'll use my num.ring.
And that concludes this video on working
with numbers.